Zachary Stoebner

Research Overview _____

I engineer new methods to process high-dimensional signals, particularly in magnetic resonance imaging, with practical benefit in mind. My research spans **signal processing**, **deep learning**, and **machine perception** to solve challenging problems in autonomous systems. Generally, my interests are in AI/ML & neuroscience, intelligent systems & robotics, and optimization & control.

Education

University of Texas at Austin

Austin, TX

PHD IN ELECTRICAL & COMPUTER ENGINEERING

August 2022 - ??

- Advisor: Prof. Jon Tamir
- Focus: Computational sensing and imaging

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

MS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

August 2021 - May 2022

- Advisor: Prof. Ipek Oguz
- Thesis: A deep learning-based automatic segmentation system for surgical endoscopy

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

. August 2017 - May 2021

BS WITH HONORS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & NEUROSCIENCE

- Minor in Applied Mathematics
- Advisor: Prof. Ipek Oguz
- Research: ML for brain MRI: (1) GAN-based harmonization and (2) cortical shape analysis using linear-mixed models

Peer-Reviewed Publications

CONFERENCE

Zachary A. Stoebner, Daiwei Lu, Seok Hee Hong, Nicholas L. Kavoussi, and Ipek Oguz, "Segmentation of kidney stones in endoscopic video feeds", Proc. SPIE 12032, Medical Imaging 2022: Image Processing, 120323G (4 April 2022).

IN REVIEW

Zachary A. Stoebner, Kilian Hett, Ilwoo Lyu, Hans Johnson, Jane S. Paulsen, Jeffrey Long, Ipek Oguz, "Comprehensive shape analysis of the cortex in Huntington's disease". Brain. 2022.

Honors & Awards _____

2022 Cockrell Engineering Fellowship, University of Texas at Austin

\$36,000

Presentations _____

POSTERS

* presenting author

Zachary A. Stoebner*, Daiwei Lu, Seok Hee Hong, Nicholas L. Kavoussi, and Ipek Oguz. "Segmentation of kidney stones in endoscopic video feeds". Vanderbilt Institute of Surgery & Engineering Symposium. 2021. Nashville, TN.

Nicholas L. Kavoussi*, **Zachary A. Stoebner**, Daiwei Lu, Ipek Oguz. "Automated Method of Tracking and Segmenting Kidney Stones During Ureteroscopy Using Computer Vision Techniques". Engineering & Urology Society Meeting. 2021. Las Vegas, NV.

TALKS

Fall 2021 ML for Course and Research Projects, CS 4262 - Foundations of ML

Vanderbilt

Teaching Experience _____

ASSISTANT

Spring 2022	Projects in ML, CS 3892	Vanderbilt
Fall 2021	Artificial Intelligence, CS 4260	Vanderbilt
Spring 2021	Deep Learning, CS 3891	Vanderbilt
Fall 2020	Operating Systems, CS 3281	Vanderbilt
Spring 2020	Discrete Structures, CS 2212	Vanderbilt
Fall 2019	Discrete Structures, CS 2212	Vanderbilt

Service & Outreach _____

2021-2022 Community Outreach Chair, Out in Engineering	Vanderbilt
2021-2022 Peer Reviewer, Section Leader, & Graduate Mentor, Undergraduate Research Journal	l Vanderbilt
2019-2021 Mentor & VP of Communications, Engineering Design Studio	Vanderbilt

Skills_____

Programming: Python, C++, C, MATLAB, R, JavaScript, LTEX

Engineering: soldering, CAD, 3D printing

Language: English (native), Portuguese (fluent), Spanish (advanced), French (basic)

Other: kū & tanka poet, nature photographer, weightlifter, trail runner